{"test_questions": [[{"question": "A competitive inhibitor of an enzyme is usually", "opta": "a highly reactive compound", "optb": "a metal ion such as Hg2+ or Pb2+", "optc": "structurally similar to the substrate.", "optd": "water insoluble", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Linear inhibition is sometimes called as", "opta": "complete inhibition", "optb": "incomplete inhibtion", "optc": "partial inhibition", "optd": "mixed inhibition", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The types of inhibition pattern based on Michaelis Menten equation are", "opta": "competitive", "optb": "non-competitive", "optc": "uncompetitive", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effect of non-competitive inhibition on a Lineweaver-Burk Plot is that", "opta": "it can move the entire curve to the right", "optb": "it can change the y-intercept", "optc": "it can change the x-intercept", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rate-determining step of Michaelis Menten kinetics is", "opta": "the complex formation step", "optb": "the complex dissociation step to produce product", "optc": "the product formation step", "optd": "Both (a)and(c)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In competitive inhibition a factor is obtained from the measurement of", "opta": "Vmax", "optb": "KM", "optc": "Y-intercept in Lineweaver-Burk Plot", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these proteases is not a cysteine active site protease?", "opta": "Calpain", "optb": "Cathepsin D", "optc": "Papain", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Given an enzyme with a Km = 10m M and Vmax = 100 m mol/min. If [S] = 100 m M, which of the following will be true?", "opta": "A 10 fold increase in Vmax would increase velocity 10 fold                                                                                           y", "optb": "A 10 fold decrease in Km would increase velocity", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "A 10 fold increase in Vmax would decrease velocity 20 fold", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The conformational change in an enzyme after the substrate is bound that allows the chemical reaction to proceed, can be explained by", "opta": "induced fit", "optb": "transition", "optc": "fit and fine", "optd": "Pasteur", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The active site of an enzyme remains", "opta": "at the center of globular proteins", "optb": "rigid and does not change shape", "optc": "complementary to the rest of the molecule", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which category of enzymes belongs to class two in the international classification?", "opta": "Hydrolases", "optb": "Ligases", "optc": "Transferases", "optd": "Isomerase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Woolf-Augusteinsson-Hofstee plot of \u03bd versus \u03bd/[S] and the Eadie-Scatchard plot of \u03bd/[S] versus \u03bd do not involve reciprocals of \u03bd therefore are considered to be more reliable when the error in v is", "opta": "non-significant", "optb": "significant", "optc": "nothing to do with the reliability", "optd": "non significant in selected cases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The relationship between Keq, Km and Vmax is known as", "opta": "Haldane equation", "optb": "Michaelis Menten equation", "optc": "Numerical solution approach", "optd": "Gibbs-Helmholtz equation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reciprocal equation for non competitive inhibition can be arranged to the equation for the", "opta": "Dixon plot", "optb": "Woolf-Augusteinsson-Hofstee plot", "optc": "Eadie-Scatchard plot", "optd": "Hanes-Woolf plot", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true for enzymatically catalyzed reaction?", "opta": "The activation energy of the reaction is lowered so that a larger proportion of the substrate qualifies to overcome it", "optb": "Additional substrate molecules are energized to overcome the activation energy of the reaction", "optc": "The activation energy of the reaction is increased, thus decreasing the likelihood that any substrate molecules will overcome it", "optd": "The activation energy of the reaction is lowered so that a fewer substrate molecules can overcome it", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following common drugs is not a specific enzyme inhibitor?", "opta": "Iodine", "optb": "Methotrexate", "optc": "Sulfbnilamide", "optd": "Penicillin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzyme inhibition can occur by", "opta": "reversible inhibitors", "optb": "irreversible inhibitors", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a Lineweaver-Burk Plot, competitive inhibitor shows which of the following effect?", "opta": "It moves the entire curve to right", "optb": "It moves the entire curve to left", "optc": "It changes the x-intercept", "optd": "It has no effect on the slope", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is not true?", "opta": "Enzymes are proteins that bind to specific substrates and increase the velocity of reactions involving those substrates", "optb": "Enzymes function by overcoming the activation energy barrier of a reaction", "optc": "Enzymes make thermodynamically favorable reactions to proceed; they cannot make unfavorable reactions to occur", "optd": "Enzymes only function when they are in intact cells", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Non-competitive inhibitor of an enzyme catalyzed reaction", "opta": "decreases Vmax", "optb": "binds to Michaelis complex (ES)", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "can actually increase reaction velocity in rare cases", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An enzyme and a reactant molecule maintain relationship as", "opta": "a temporary association", "optb": "an association stabilized by a covalent bond", "optc": "one in which the enzyme is changed permanently", "optd": "non complementary binding", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An enzyme is assayed at an initial substrate concentration of 2 x 10-5M. In 6 minute, half of the substrate is used. The Km for the substrate is 2 x 10-3M. The value of k in minute is", "opta": "0.115", "optb": "0.42", "optc": "0.093", "optd": "6.693", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The plot commonly used for determining the value of Vmax is", "opta": "Lineweaver Burk plot", "optb": "Langmuir plot", "optc": "Eadie Hofstee plot", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Quasi steady state is also known as", "opta": "Michaelis Menten approach", "optb": "Briggs-Haldane approach", "optc": "Pseudo steady state", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these enzymes contains a Zinc (Zn) ion?", "opta": "Carboxypeptidase A", "optb": "Phosphorylase B kinase", "optc": "Tyrosine hydroxylase", "optd": "Phosphodiesterase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A noncompetitive inhibitor of an enzyme-catalyzed reaction", "opta": "increases KM and increases Vmax", "optb": "increases KM and reduces Vmax", "optc": "reduces KM and increases Vmax", "optd": "reduces KM and reduces Vmax", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An allosteric inhibitor of an enzyme usually", "opta": "participates in feedback regulation", "optb": "denatures the enzyme", "optc": "is a hydrophobic compound", "optd": "causes the enzyme to work faster", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following activity is possible by transferases?", "opta": "Transfer of methyl groups", "optb": "Transfer of glycosyl group", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A classical uncompetitive inhibitor is a compound that binds", "opta": "reversibly to the enzyme substrate complex yielding an inactive ESI complex", "optb": "irreversibly to the enzyme substrate complex yielding an inactive ESI complex", "optc": "reversibly to the enzyme substrate complex yielding an active ESI complex", "optd": "irreversibly to the enzyme substrate complex yielding an active ESI complex", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which graphical method is used to determine an enzyme degree of cooperativity?", "opta": "Hill plot", "optb": "Koshland curve", "optc": "Michaelis-Menten hyperbola", "optd": "Can not be determined", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}